africa.com 2017-10-03

# AFRICA.COM Privacy Policy - Africa.com

**This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices for Africa.com and Africa.comDEALS.**

________________________________________

This privacy policy covers www.africa.com. Because Africa.com wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices. If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact Customer Service by sending an e-mail to support@africa.com.  
________________________________________

**WHAT INFORMATION DO WE GATHER ABOUT YOU?**

The information we gather falls into two categories: 1) Personally identifiable information, which includes personal information you voluntarily supply when you subscribe, order, complete a survey, register for an online discussion, enter a contest or provide your e-mail address and 2) Non-personally identifiable information, which includes tracking information collected as you navigate through our sites.

**Personally Identifiable Information**

**Registration for our Web sites**  
Anyone can view our sites, but a free registration process is required to access the full range of information and services offered across our different sites. Africa.com requires that you supply certain personally identifiable information, including a unique e-mail address and demographic information (zip code, age, sex, household income (optional), job industry and job title) to register. By using Africa.com, you are agreeing to our Terms of Service. Contests, Sweepstakes and Special Offers

On occasion, Africa.com collects personal information from readers in connection with optional sweepstakes, contests or special offers. If this information is to be shared with a third party other than Africa.com, we will notify you at the time of collection. If you do not want any personal information shared, you may always decline to participate in the sweepstakes, contest or special offer.

**Reader Surveys, Reader Panels and Market Research**  
Africa.com may collect personal information from readers in connection with voluntary surveys. Data may be collected on our Web sites. The information you provide in answer to optional survey questions may be shared, but only in the aggregate, with advertisers and partners unless we notify you otherwise at the time of collection. All survey data is reported and/or used in aggregate form only, and no personally identifiable information is released. From time to time, we may use different technologies, including cookies, to better understand answers to our surveys.

**Mobile Messaging Service**  
Africa.com uses the information collected from your interaction with Africa.com by Text Messaging Service (SMS) (“SMS Service”) solely for the purposes of improving the SMS Service. The information will not be provided, sold, licensed, rented, assigned or disclosed to Third Parties, except as required by law, nor will we use your phone number to initiate a call or SMS text message to you without your express prior consent. Your wireless carrier and other service providers also collect data about your SMS Service usage, and their practices are governed by their own privacy policies. Africa.com collects the mobile phone number you use to send us a text message and the content of the messages sent between you and Africa.com. When you send a text message to Africa.com or via Africa.com, we log the incoming phone number, the wireless provider associated with the number, and the date and time of the transaction. The only information we automatically collect is that related to the use of our Mobile Services. Africa.com uses this data to analyze the message traffic in order to operate, develop and improve our SMS Service.

**Non-personally Identifiable Information**  
In addition to personally identifiable information, we also collect certain non-personally identifiable information through technology and tools, including cookies and log data. We aggregate and analyze this information in order to learn more about how our Web sites are used.

**Cookies from Us**  
As is standard practice on many Web sites, we use “cookies” and other technologies to recognize you and provide personalization, as well as to help us understand, where our visitors are going and how much time they spend there. You will not be able to access certain areas of our Web sites, including Africa.com, if your computer does not accept cookies from us.

**Cookies from Advertisers**  
Some advertisements on certain of our Web sites (including Africa.com) are served by third-party advertising companies. In the course of serving these advertisements, these advertisers may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser in order to collect certain non-personally identifiable information about your visits to our Web sites and other Web sites.

We do not have access to, nor control over, advertisers’ cookies or how they may be used. Google is one of the companies that serves advertisements onto Africa.com. It uses the DART cookie to serve ads based on your visit to Africa.com and other sites on the Internet. You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences "Google ad and content network privacy policy"). Your access to our Web sites will not be affected if you do not accept cookies served by third parties.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: [http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](https://www.africa.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/opt_out.asp "http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp").

**IP Addresses**  
Africa.com logs Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, or the location of your computer on the Internet, for systems administration and troubleshooting purposes. We use this information in an aggregate fashion to track access to our Web sites.

**WHAT DO WE DO WITH THE INFORMATION WE GATHER ABOUT YOU?**

**Statistical Analysis**  
Africa.com may perform statistical, demographic and marketing analyses of subscribers, and their subscribing and purchasing patterns, for product development purposes and to generally inform advertisers about the nature of our subscriber base. We also use such information to allow advertising to be targeted, in aggregate, to the users for whom such advertising is most pertinent. Africa.com may share personal information with Africa.com Company for analysis purposes, including analysis to improve customer relationships.

**Products and Services from Africa.com**  
From time to time, we may provide subscribers with information and offers about other products and services offered by Africa.com, including subscriptions and other premium products and services. This information will only be shared internally.

**Banner Advertising**  
We may use demographic and preference information to allow advertising on our Web sites to be targeted, in aggregate, to the users for whom they are most pertinent. This means users see advertising that is most likely to interest them, and advertisers send their messages to people who are most likely to be receptive, improving both the viewer’s experience and the effectiveness of the ads. We will disclose information to third parties only in aggregate form.

User Generated Content (Including Comments, Reader Reviews and TimesPeople)  
We offer opportunities for you to engage in public activities on Africa.com, including submitting comments, recommendations, reader reviews and ratings in a number of areas throughout Africa.com. Any information you disclose in your submissions, along with your screen name or ID, or any image or photo, becomes public and may be used by Africa.com for online and offline promotional or commercial uses in any and all media. If you chose to engage in public activities on the site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these areas, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. For more information, read the Forums, Discussions and User Generated Content section of the Terms of Service.

**E-Mail Newsletters**  
If you choose to receive them, Africa.com will periodically send you e-mail newsletters or promotional e-mail about services offered by Africa.com and its advertisers.

**WHAT IS OUR E-MAIL POLICY?**

Africa.com complies fully with the federal CAN-SPAM Act of 2003. We will not share, sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to use your e-mail address without your permission. If you feel you have received an e-mail from us in error, please contact support@Africa.com.

Account and Service-Related E-mail: Africa.com reserves the right to send you e-mail relating to your account status. This includes order confirmations, renewal/expiration notices, notices of credit-card problems, other transactional e-mails and notifications about major changes to our Web sites and/or to our Privacy Policy. If you have registered for online discussions or other services, you may receive e-mail specific to your participation in those activities. E-mail Newsletters: Africa.com offers several e-mail newsletters. If you no longer wish to receive a specific newsletter, follow the “unsubscribe” instructions located near the bottom of each newsletter.

Promotional E-mail: If you choose to receive them, Africa.com may periodically e-mail you messages about products and services that we think may be of interest to you. You can choose not to receive messages in the future by following the “unsubscribe” instructions located near the bottom of each e-mail. From time to time, Africa.com may obtain e-mail addresses from third party sources to be used for promotional e-mails. You can choose not to receive messages in the future by following the “unsubscribe” instructions located near the bottom of each e-mail.

Survey E-mail: We may send you an e-mail inviting you to participate in user surveys, asking for feedback on Africa.com and existing or prospective products and services, as well as information to better understand our users. User surveys greatly help us to improve our Web site, and any information we obtain in such surveys will not be shared with third parties, except in aggregate form.

HTML E-mail: When you sign up to receive e-mail from us, you can select either plain text or HTML (with images) format. If you select the HTML format, we may place a one-pixel gif to determine whether or not readers viewed the e-mail. This process does not leave any information on your computer, nor does it collect information from your computer. Africa.com may share this data with others in aggregate only.

E-mails From You: If you send us e-mails, you should be aware that information disclosed in e-mails may not be secure or encrypted and thus may be available to others. We suggest that you exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal or confidential information in e-mails. We will use your e-mail address to respond directly to your questions or comments.

E-mail This Article Feature: Africa.com readers may use this feature to e-mail links to articles (or other content such as slideshows). The e-mail addresses that you supply to this service are saved for your convenience for future articles you may wish to e-mail; these addressses are not used for any other purpose, and will not be shared with any third parties.

**WITH WHOM DO WE SHARE THE INFORMATION THAT WE GATHER?**

**Africa.com**  
If you have registered to one of our sites, Africa.com will not sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to use your e-mail address or any information that personally identifies you without your permission. We do, however, share information about our audience in aggregate form.

**Service Providers**  
We contract with other companies to provide services on our behalf, including credit-card and billing processing, shipping, e-mail distribution, list processing and analytics or promotions management. We provide these companies only with the information they need to perform their services. These service providers are restricted from using this data in any way other than to provide services for Africa.com, and they may not share or resell this data. We reserve the right to disclose your opt-out information to third parties so they can suppress your name from future solicitations, in accordance with applicable laws. We may occasionally release personal information as required by law, for example, to comply with a court order or subpoena. (For more information, see the “Compliance with legal process” section of this policy.)

**HOW DO I OPT-OUT FROM RECEIVING PROMOTIONAL OFFERS?**

**E-mail Promotions**  
If, at any time, you prefer not to receive e-mail marketing information from us, simply follow the unsubscribe options at the bottom of each e-mail.  
IS MY INFORMATION PROTECTED?

Data Security: To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place physical, electronic and managerial procedures to protect the information we collect online. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

**OTHER INFORMATION: Compliance with Legal Process**  
We may disclose personal information if we are required to do so by law or we in good faith believe that such action is necessary to (1) comply with the law or with legal process; (2) protect and defend our rights and property; (3) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of our Web sites; or (4) protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public (among other things, this means that if you provide false information or attempt to pose as someone else, information about you may be disclosed as part of any investigation into your actions).

**OTHER INFORMATION: Children’s Guidelines**  
COPPA Compliance: Africa.com does not knowingly collect or store any personal information, even in aggregate, about children under the age of 13.

These children’s guidelines have been developed with the recognition that Internet technology evolves rapidly and that underlying business models are still not established. Accordingly, guidelines are subject to change. In the unlikely event of such changes they will be posted on this page. If the changes represent a material departure from our current practice with respect to the use of children’s personal information, the changes will be posted on this page thirty days prior to taking effect and will not affect children’s personal information previously collected.

**OTHER INFORMATION: Changes to This Policy**  
This Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time. Any such changes will be posted on this page. If we make a significant or material change in the way we use your personal information, the change will be posted on this page thirty (30) days prior to taking effect and registered users will be notified via e-mail.

_Last Updated on January 1st, 2014_
